Guide to the Frederick C. Tanner Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Frederick C. Tanner Papers,
1911-[ca. 1928]
Tanner, Frederick C. (Frederick Chauncey), 1878-1963.
ca. 6,500 items (17 boxes, 18 v.)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079388
Biographical Note
Lawyer, chairman of the New York State Republican Party, 1914-1917.
Scope and Content
Files of political correspondence and papers of Tanner. The majority of the correspondence deals with city and state elections. The correspondents include Charles Evans Hughes, Theodore Roosevelt, Franklin D. Roosevelt, William Howard Taft, and Fiorello La Guardia. Also, a collection of eighteen scrapbooks.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 4 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Arranged Correspondence
Series III: Clippings and Pamphlets
Series IV: Scrapbooks
Subjects
Republican Party (N.Y.); Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947.; Elections--New York (State); Elections--New York (State)--New York.; Political parties--New York (State); Scrapbooks.; Lawyers.; Politicians.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-18. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
03/--/61 M-61-03 Tanner, Frederick C. via the Oral History Office Gift
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray -- Hayward, William H. -- Hughes, Charles Evans -- LaGuardia, Fiorello H. -- Mitchel, John Purroy -- Roosevelt, Franklin Delano -- Roosevelt, Theodore -- Root, Elihu -- Stimson, Hanry L. -- Taft, William Howard -- Tanner, Frederick C. (Box 1)
- Series II: Arranged Correspondence
  - Correspondence, [v.p.], 1911/1912 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, [v.p.], 1912 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, [v.p.], 1913 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, [v.p.], 1914 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, [v.p.], 1915 & 1915 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, [v.p.], 1917 - 1922 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence concerning appointments and positions (Box 8)
  - Correspondence relating to Whitman Dinner, New York, 1912 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence relating to Reconstruction Commission, New York, 1919/1920 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence relating to League to Enforce Peace, New York, 1915 - 1919 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence relating to Fusion Campaign, New York, 1917 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence relating to Coalition, New York, 1917/1918 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence relating to Congressional matters, New York, 1918 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence relating to Hughes Alliance, New York, 1916 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence relating to O'Malley Campaign, New York, 1919 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence relating to Ordway, Downing, and Nevin Campaigns, New York, 1917/1918 (Box 9)
  - New York State Republican Convention, New York, 1915 (Box 10)
  - New York State Constitutional Convention, New York, 1915 (Box 10)
  - New York State County politics (Box 11)
  - Material used in connection with Mr. Tanner's Oral History Reminiscences (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 12)
- Series III: Clippings and Pamphlets
  - Clippings and pamphlets (Box 13)
- Series IV: Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook No. 1, November 1911 - April 1913 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook No. 2, May 1913 - June 1914 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook No. 3, June 1914 - October 1914 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook No. 4, October 1914 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook No. 5, October 1914 - Novermber 1914 (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook No. 6, November 1914 - December 1914 (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook No. 7, December 1914 - March 1915 (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook No. 8, March 1915 - May 1915 (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook No. 9, May 1915 - August 1915 (Box 16)
  - Scrapbook No. 10, August 1915 - October 1915 (Box 16)
  - Scrapbook No. 11, October 1915 - February 1916 (Box 16)
  - Scrapbook No. 12, February 1916 - April 1916 (Box 16)
  - Scrapbook No. 13, April 1916 (Box 17)
  - Scrapbook No. 14, April 1916 - June 1916 (Box 17)
  - Scrapbook No. 15, June 1916 - September 1916 (Box 17)
  - Scrapbook No. 16, October 1916 - January 1917 (Box 17)
  - Scrapbook No. 17, January 1917 - September 1918 (Box 18)
  - Scrapbook No. 18, September 1918 - May 1921 (Box 18)